Social Briars is a comedy, drama film directed by Henry King.
Iris Lee is reared in the small town of Dalton by her deceased mother's friend, Martha
Kane, and when she reaches adulthood, Martha's son Jim falls in love with her.
When Iris fails to return his affections, Mrs.
Kane treats her so coldly that Iris decides to leave the
stuffy little village for the metropolis.
On her journey, she accepts a ride with Jack Andrews, but after he attempts to
kiss her, she leaps from the car and walks the rest of the way.
While singing in the choir of a large metropolitan church, she is discovered by
Jack's wealthy father Peter, who recommends her as a soloist.
Light opera star Helen Manning, who has helped Iris to cultivate her voice,
quarrels with her theatrical manager, and Iris is offered her position.
Iris Lee, played by Mary Miles Minter.
Jack Andrews, played by Allan Forrest.
Martha Kane, played by Anne Schaefer.
Jim Kane, played by Edmund Cobb.
Peter Andrews, played by George Periolat.
Helen Manning, played by Claire Du Brey.
Social Briars is a 1918 American silent comedy-drama film
directed by Henry King and starring  Mary Miles Minter.
The story was by Jeanne Judson, and it was filmed under the working title of "The Greater
Call." As with many of Minter's features, it is thought to be a lost film.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.